Guide to the Histadrut Records, 1956-1990 AIS.2010.08
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Histadrut Records
1956-1990
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Histadrut ha-kelalit shel ha-'ovdim be-Erets-Yisra'el
AIS.2010.08
1.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
The General Federation of Laborers in the Land of Israel, or Histadrut, is Israel's organization of trade unions and the largest voluntary organization in the country. Histadrut became a powerful figure in the Labour Zionist movement as well as a significant employer and state builder within Israel. This collection includes a variety of pamphlets regarding the work of Histadrut in Israel and American Histadrut organizations in the United States.
Previous Citation
Histadrut Records, 1956-1990, AIS.2010.08, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
History
The General Federation of Labor in Israel, or Histadrut, is Israel's organization of trade unions and the largest voluntary organization in the country. The organization was created in 1920 to champion the interests of Jewish workers in the city of Haifa. Histadrut became a powerful figure in the Labour Zionist movement as well as a significant employer and state builder within Israel. The organization has many arms which are active in various aspects of Israeli life including health care, the economy, and education. In 1960, Arab workers were admitted with full membership. During the 1980s and 1990s, Histadrut sold much of its holdings to private companies, but is still part owner in a variety of industries. Histadrut is a member of the International Trade Union Confederation.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes a variety of pamphlets regarding the work of Histadrut in Israel. Many of these pamphlets and publications also document the activities of American Histadrut organizations, including the Pittsburgh Histadrut Council.
Correspondence; Labor unions -- Israel -- History -- 20th century; Ethnic groups; Pamphlets; Labor; Articles; American Histadrut Cultural Exchange Institute; Pittsburgh Histadrut Council; Histadrut ha-kelalit shel ha-'ovdim be-Erets-Yisra'el
- Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Articles (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Attitudes by the Labour Zionist Movement, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pittsburgh Histadrut Council, Annual Histadrut Tribute Dinner-Dance, 1981-1985, 1987 (Box 1, Item 1-8)
- Pioneer Women and Histadrut: The Story of Pioneer Women's 40th Anniversary Project (Box 1, Item 9)
- Western Pennsylvania Unions Build The Steel City Clinic (Box 1, Item 10)
- Invitation, Mid-Winter Conference of the Israel Histadrut Campaign, February 13, 1972 (Box 1, Item 11)
- The Working Woman in Israel by Naava Eisin, 1975 (Box 1, Item 12)
- Calling American Labor to Join... (Box 1, Item 13)
- The Israeli Incursion into Lebanon: A Personal Report and Reflections on My Trip to Israel and Lebanon by Bayard Rustin, August 15-23, 1982 (Box 1, Item 14)
- L'Histadrout: Organisation Syndicale et Cooperative des Travailleurs en Israel by A. Abramson, 1970 (Box 1, Item 15)
- Histadrut: A Profile by Dan Giladi and Sarah Morris, 1979 (Box 1, Item 16)
- Jubilee of Histadrut: Achievements and Aims of the Israel Labor Federation by Aharon Becker, 1972 (Box 1, Item 17)
- Histadrut: Shaping A New Society, 1971 (Box 1, Item 18)
- The Histadrut, Reprint from the Jerusalem Post Supplement, February 17, 1956 (Box 1, Item 19)
- The Histadrut (Box 1, Item 20)
- Jewish-Arab Relations in Israel by Eliahu Elath, 1967 (Box 1, Item 21)
- Mutual Aid and Social Medicine in Israel by Itzhak Kanev, 1960 (Box 1, Item 22)
- Histadrut Award Dinner "Roasting" Rosemary Trump and Harold S. Bigler, September 16, 1990 (Box 1, Item 23)
- Social Insurance and Voluntary Health, Welfare, Pension Programs in Israel by Sherman G. Sass, 1968 (Box 1, Item 24)
- US Labor Editors Look at Israel: Reports to American Union Members on a Memorable Visit to a Beleaguered Democracy (Box 1, Item 25)
- Seminar on Cooperation, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Item 26)
- Under the Stars of Negev, December 18, 1965 (Box 1, Item 27)
- Sportsman of the Year Testimonial Dinner Saluting Judge William F. Cercone, September 21, 1967 (Box 1, Item 28)
- The Future is Here (Box 1, Item 29)
- One People One Destiny: United Jewish Federation of Greater Pittsburgh, Annual Report, 1986 (Box 1, Item 30)
- Testimonial Dinner in Tribute to Honorable Henry M. Jackson United States Senator, State of Washington in Behalf of the Histadrut Scholarship Fund, May 14, 1974 (Box 1, Item 31)
- Senator Richard S. Schweiker Testimonial Dinner, January 25, 1971 (Box 1, Item 32)
- Thomas DiLauro - William Ross Tribute Dinner Tendered by the American Trade Union Council for Histadrut, October 11, 1964 (Box 1, Item 33)
- Pioneers at Work, Histadrut in Action (Box 1, Item 34)
- 142nd Anniversary: B'nai B'rith NYSA Campaign, 1985 (Box 1, Item 35)
- Issue Analysis by the American Zionist Federation Program Department, January 1986 (Box 1, Item 36)
- Jewish Population Study of Greater Pittsburgh, Community Report, 1986 (Box 1, Item 37)
- Man and His Brother: The Afro-Asian Institute for Co-operative and Labour Studies, 1967 (Box 1, Item 38)
- The Cultural, Medical Help and Assistance Fund of the General Federation of Jewish Labour in Eretz-Israel, Financial Statements, 1965 (Box 1, Item 39)
- 'Amal': The Story of Histadrut's Build-Up of Israel's Industrial Skills (Box 1, Item 40)
- Projects Submitted by the National Committee for Labor Israel (Box 1, Item 41)
- Angelo A. Carboni Testimonial Dinner, November 15, 1969 (Box 1, Item 42)
- How to Get More for the Money You're Spending on Postage and Mailing, 1978 (Box 1, Item 43)
- Fifteenth Silver Anniversary Banquet of the Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers Local Union No. 3, September 15, 1979 (Box 1, Item 44)
- American Federation of Teachers Local 2067 Community College of Allegheny County Second Annual Caring Fund Dinner to Benefit Genesis House, February 12, 1988 (Box 1, Item 45)
- The Judge William F. Cercone Scholarship Foundation of the Histadrut Scholarship Fund Testimonial, December 18, 1965 (Box 1, Item 46)